<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrea De Polis</title>
    <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://andreadepolis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Andrea De Polis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Andrea De Polis</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://andreadepolis.github.io/media/icon_hubffddc73fe8e4f51a11ee5abe71c28fc_2383_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Andrea De Polis</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Forecasting Macroeconomics Downside Risk</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/publication/downsiderisk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/publication/downsiderisk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We model secular trends and cyclical changes of the predictive density of US GDP growth. A substantial increase in downside risk to US economic growth emerges over the last 30 years, associated with the long-run growth slowdown started in the early 2000s. Conditional skewness moves procyclically, implying negatively skewed predictive densities ahead and during recessions, often anticipated by deteriorating financial conditions, while positively skewed distributions characterize expansions. The modelling framework ensures robustness to tail events, allows for either dense or sparse predictor designs, and delivers competitive out-of-sample (point, density and tail) forecasts, improving upon standard benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Risks and Common Gaps</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/commonrisks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/commonrisks.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Okun’s law puts forward a relation between the output and the unemployment gaps. I provide evidence of common non-linearities across the two quantities, highlighting common dynamics in higher order moments. I estimate a joint model for the dynamics of the marginal densities of the output gap and the unemployment gap, which can capture potential non-Gaussian features of the data through the time variation of the mean, variance and skewness. I postulate the Okun’s relation to hold for the predictive densities by assuming common cyclical components for the moments. I document a considerable reduction in the uncertainty surrounding estimates of the natural rate of unemployment, or NAIRU, in the US, as compared to estimates based on symmetric models. Simi- larly, accounting for time-varying skewness of the output delivers estimates of the output gap that are less uncertain and more stable over time with respect to CBO projections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing for Conditional Skewness with Epsilon-Skew-t Distributions.</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/skewtest.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/skewtest.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I develop a parametric test to detect the presence of instability in the third moment of time series data. The test is based on the score function of the flexible epsilon-Skew-t distribution, and belongs to the class of Lagrange Multiplier tests. The test presents appropriate asymptotic properties, as evaluated by means of an extensive Monte Carlo analysis. When applied to the three asset pricing anomalies of Fama and French (1993), the test points at an overwelimg evidence of con- ditional non-Gaussianity at the daily frequency, whereas weaker results are observed at the monthly frequency. These results should be taken as a warning of possible misspecification of asset pricing models based on symmetric likelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dynamics of Macroeconomic Downside Risk</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/policywork/suerfdownsiderisk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/policywork/suerfdownsiderisk.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taming of the Skew: Asymmetric Inflation Risk and Monetary Policy</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/inflationrisk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/inflationrisk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inflation risk in U.S. data varies significantly over time and often exhibits asymmetry. We introduce an econometric model with time-varying asymmetric risk that outperforms a state-of-the-art symmetric model in forecasting accuracy and achieves results comparable to those of professional forecasters. Skewness in the inflation distribution introduces a wedge between the expected value of future inflation and the modal forecast. We show that this wedge can be formalized within a linear-quadratic DSGE model by deriving the \textit{beliefs representation of asymmetric risk} of that model. This approach enables us to solve analytically for optimal monetary policy in stylized models and to explore the implications of skewed risk on macroeconomic outcomes in quantitative DSGE models. The optimal policy requires the central bank to take measures that shift the modal forecasts for inflation in the opposite direction of the asymmetric risk. We demonstrate the practical implications of this policy approach by aligning the beliefs representation of a quantitative DSGE model to reflect the inflation skewness estimated by the econometric model using U.S. data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming Momentum Crashes</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/momentum.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/momentum.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We provide empirical evidence that the returns on US equity momentum exhibit a time-varying skewness which deepens during dramatic losses (crashes). As a result, the dynamics of the strategy expected returns reflects the time variation in {\it both} conditional volatility and skewness. This has first order implications for managing risks associated with momentum investing: an adjusted momentum portfolio which hedges in real time for both volatility and skewness risk outperforms benchmark constant and dynamic volatility-managed momentum strategies. This result holds for different levels of transaction costs and risk aversion and cannot be reconciled by the exposure to standard equity risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Rate Dynamics and Unconventional Monetary Policies: It&#39;s All in the Shadows</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/exchagerate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/exchagerate.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper we estimate an open economy New-Keynesian model to investigate the impact of unconventional monetary policies on the exchange rate, focusing on those adopted since the Global Financial Crisis in the euro area and in the United States. To this end we replace effective, short-term, interest rates with shadow rates, which provide a measure of the monetary stance when the former reach their effective lower bound. We find that since 2009, unconventional monetary policies significantly affected the dynamics of the euro-dollar exchange rate both in nominal and real terms. While the stimulus provided by the Fed prevailed between 2011 and 2014, contributing to the weakening of the dollar, in most recent years the depreciation of the euro mainly reflected the measures adopted by the ECB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ever-Changing Challenges to Price Stability</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/everchanging.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/everchanging.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US inflation risk is non-symmetric and varies considerably over time. Monetary and fiscal policies along with non-policy factors, such as unit labor costs, long-run interest rates, the unemployment gap, and commodity prices, are key drivers of the inflation risk. Macroeconomic predictors affect the long-run mean of inflation chiefly by influencing the shape and the skewness of the predictive distribution of long-run inflation. Inflation stabilization requires periodic revisions to the monetary and fiscal framework to counterbalance persistent shifts in the inflation risk. Failing to offset the inflation risk led to the large upside inflation risk of the 1960s and the 1970s. Our findings suggest that the Phillips curve is nonlinear and its slope is affected by policy and non-policy factors that have bearings on short-term volatility and risk of inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Frequency Functional VARs for Nowcasting and Structural Analysis</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/incomenowcasting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/incomenowcasting.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We propose a functional-Vector Autoregressive model (fVAR) to nowcast the dynamics of the whole income distribution in the United Kingdom. British survey data about household income are published by the Office for National Statistics (ONS) with considerable delay, making them un- appealing for policy evaluation. Our approach produces accurate predictions of past, current and future income distributions. We introduce a framework to rank the predictive ability of forecasting models when the target object is a full density, rather than a single realization. Based on this novel loss-function, we establish that out fVAR provides superior forecasting accuracy with respect to com- peting models. Our model further allows to carry out structural analysis on the income distribution within a traditional VAR setting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Forecasting with High-Frequency Seasonal Patterns</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/weeklyinterpolation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workinprogress/weeklyinterpolation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose a novel, comprehensive approach to interpolate low-frequency of- ficial statistics from high-frequency data. Differently from standard mixed-frequency dynamic factor models, commonly used for nowcasting, we leverage on recent developments in nowcasting modeling to build a methodology that can easily deal with outlier detection, complex calendar patterns and temporal disaggregation. We deploy the new methodology to introduce a new weekly tracker for real activity in the United Kingdom based on the several new, high-frequency data provided by the Office for National Statistics (ONS). Results suggest that these new data sources, when properly managed via our model, introduce significant improvements in the predictive accuracy of traditional nowcasting models, generally based on lower-frequency data, in terms of both point and density forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/slides/example.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/slides/example.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   One 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   **Two** 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   Three 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/media/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/admin.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/admin.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
