<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ivan Petrella | Andrea De Polis</title>
    <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/authors/petrella.html</link>
      <atom:link href="https://andreadepolis.github.io/authors/petrella/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ivan Petrella</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Andrea De Polis</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://andreadepolis.github.io/media/icon_hubffddc73fe8e4f51a11ee5abe71c28fc_2383_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ivan Petrella</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/authors/petrella.html</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taming of the Skew: Asymmetric Inflation Risk and Monetary Policy</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/inflationrisk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/inflationrisk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inflation risk in U.S. data varies considerably over time and has often been asymmetric. A
model incorporating time-varying asymmetric risk achieves better forecasting accuracy than a
state-of-the-art symmetric model, providing results comparable to the performance of profes-
sional forecasters. The optimal monetary strategy calls for the Central Bank to counterbalance
shifts in the direction of inflation risk by adjusting its inflation target –a strategy we term risk-
adjusted inflation targeting (RAIT). By adjusting the modal inflation scenario, the Central
Bank can realign average inflation with its desired long-run inflation objective and effectively
anchor the private sector’s expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming Momentum Crashes</title>
      <link>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/momentum.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreadepolis.github.io/workingpapers/momentum.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We provide empirical evidence that the returns on US equity momentum exhibit a time-varying skewness which deepens during dramatic losses (crashes). As a result, the dynamics of the strategy expected returns reflects the time variation in {\it both} conditional volatility and skewness. This has first order implications for managing risks associated with momentum investing: an adjusted momentum portfolio which hedges in real time for both volatility and skewness risk outperforms benchmark constant and dynamic volatility-managed momentum strategies. This result holds for different levels of transaction costs and risk aversion and cannot be reconciled by the exposure to standard equity risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
